Finding Aid for the Katherine Philips Edson Papers LSC.0235
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence (1909-1920)
  - (1918), 96 pieces
    - Mary J. Workman., Labor, radicalism and reaction. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Jessica Peixotto., Council of Defense, Marie L. Obenauer, Secretary William B. Wilson. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Dr.B. Mossinsky (?)., Refusing invitation. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Elsinore R. Crowell., Possibility of article about Katherine Philips Edson and Hiram Johnson, William D. Stephens. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Anne Mumford. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Myrtle S. Francis., Land Army plan. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - A.H. Naftzger--Oscar Mueller., Myrtle Shepherd Francis, Women's Land Army. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - W.F. Dunning (?)., Job application. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Myrtle S. Francis., Women's Land Army. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Elsinore R. Crowell., Article on Katherine Philips Edson and California government. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Clement C. Young., Young's decision to run for Lieutenant Governor. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Grace C. Simons., Women's Land Army, Myrtle Shepherd Francis. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Myrtle Shepherd Francis., Land Army organization. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Atholl McBean. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Atholl McBean--Martha Blomme., Answering letter about service abroad. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Flora Stephens., Invitation. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (telegram) Charlotte Ebbets., Land Army appointment for Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - L.A. Ireland--Ben F. Schlesinger., Social health insurance and non-allopathic medicine. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger--L.A. Ireland., Social health insurance and Chamber of Commerce Committee. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - L.A. Ireland--Ben F. Schlesinger., Health insurance, allopathic and homeopathic medicine, vaccination. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger--L.A. Ireland. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Charlotte Ebetts. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (telegram) Charlotte Ebetts. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (telegram) Charlotte Ebetts. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (telegram) Charlotte Ebetts. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Josephine Goldmark--Ben F. Schlesinger., Minimum wage. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger--O. M. Billings., Social health insurance. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Retail selling course. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - L.A. Ireland--Ben F. Schlesinger., Social health insurance, non-allopathic medicine, Tom Skeyhill case. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Health insurance. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Meyer Lissner--Theodore Roosevelt., British Labor Party platform, economic inequality, public works program for unemployment, trade unions, single tax, government ownership of railroads, life insurance and industrial insurance, protective tariff, income tax and inheritance tax, Albert J. Beveridge. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Will H. Hays. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Jessica B. Peixotto., Council of Defense. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Meyer Lissner--Jay O. Hayes., Hayes' attack on Industrial Accident Commission, work of the Commission, California government efficiency, progressive and reactionaries, Hiram Johnson, government spending and public welfare, California taxation. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger--Dr. Peter Janss., State Senator William E. Brown, interest on loans, San Francisco Remedial Loan Association. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Martin C. Madsen., Requesting figures on cost and public service of Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Annette A. Adams., Acknowledging congratulations. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Mary E. McDowell. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Ralph P. Merritt--Marshall De Motte., Industrial Welfare Commission, Katherine Philips Edson, canning industry, women in war industry. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Martin C. Madsen., Conference of state officials called by War Labor Policies Board. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Marian Mel. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (telegram) Felix Frankfurter--Judge Frank Murasky., Asking for leave from Industrial Welfare Commission for Katherine Philips Edson to engage in program involving women in war effort. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Meyer Lissner--William D. Stephens., Recommending Walter Mathewson for Highway Commission vacancy. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Meyer Lissner., Walter Mathewson's chances for appointment, John S. Mitchell, Darlington. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (telegram) George L. Bell., Asking Katherine Philips Edson's presence in East. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Meyer Lissner., Appointment for Walter Mathewson. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (telegram) George L. Bell. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - (telegram) A.B.C. Dohrmann--Felix Frankfurter., Agreeing to release Katherine Philips Edson for war effort work. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - George L. Bell--A.B.C. Dohrmann., Change in plans regarding women in industry and war effort. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Louis W. Myers., Asking for support in gaining judicial appointment. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Raymond Benjamin., Acknowledging contribution to Republican State Committee. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - William F. Dunning., Robert Hague, Hiram Johnson, armistice. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Meyer Lissner (?). (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Hiram Johnson., Political situation and reform in California, Woodrow Wilson's trip to England. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Edward Krehbiel., Thanking Katherine Philips Edson for help with Home Service Institute of the Red Cross. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - (1919), 74 pieces
    - Edward A. Dickson., Los Angeles Express and social principles. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. Benjamin Nicoll-Florence Kelley., Fruit packing in California. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Carrie C. Catt., Convention of National American Woman Suffrage Association, Margaret Dreier Robins. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Florence Kelley., Women's Joint Legislative Campaign. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - (telegram) Mary S. Gibson. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - (telegram) Julia George. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Hiram Johnson--John F. Brady., Directing Brady to information on California laws passed 1911-17, John Francis Neylan. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - John F. Brady--Meyer Lissner., Asking help in getting information on Johnson's governorship in order to back him for presidential nomination. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Meyer Lissner--Hiram Johnson., Suggestions for progressive federal legislation, Peace Treaty and League of Nations, universal military training, Lloyd George, Russia, readjustment to peace-time economy--retraining, etc., businessman's attitude, Theodore Roosevelt, tribunal for industrial disputes, compensation, personal liberty and hysteria, Mary Gibson, standard citizenship requirements, Hugh Gibson, public ownership of telephones and railroads, inflation, taxation, natural resources, U.S. Supreme Court, woman suffrage. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - (telegram) Mary Garrett Hay., Woman suffrage, Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Paul A. Sinsheimer. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Hiram Johnson., Woman suffrage amendment in Senate. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Meyer Lissner., Woman participation in conference, Chester Rowell, John Francis Neylan, George I. Cochrane. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Johnson for President Committee., Democratic national administration, Hiram Johnson's gubernatorial record, conference to work for Johnson's nomination on Republican ticket. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Carrie C. Catt--Mrs. Robert Dean., Woman suffrage, formation of Leagues of Women Voters, Ratification Committee for federal amendment, Clara Burdette. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Carrie C. Catt--Mrs. Robert Dean., Need for special legislative sessions for state ratification of suffrage amendment, next presidential election and issues: League of Nations and prohibition, women voters in Europe. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Carrie C. Catt--Clara Burdette., Two Letters to Mrs. Robert Dean. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Mrs. Henry W. Rogers., Suffrage amendment, League of Women Voters. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Mary Sumner Boyd., Requesting information on minimum wage. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Chester Rowell., Woman suffrage, presidential possibitilites, Blaney, John Francis Neylan, Woodrow Wilson, Hiram Johnson, soldiers' opinions, League of Nations issue. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Florence Kelley., Industrial Welfare Commission, minimum wage, seating for packers. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Mary S. Gibson., Organizing for Hiram Johnson, League of Nations, Shelley Tolhurst, Frances Noel. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - (telegram) Clara Burdette., League of Women Voters. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ralph P. Merritt., Wage scale decision Proclamation by Governor William D. Stephens, and Wage Scale Decision by Ralph P. Merritt. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Recommending Anne M. Skidmore. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Grace C. Simons., Woman suffrage meeting, William D. Stephens, 8-hour day in government institutions. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Meyer Lissner. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Jessica B. Peixotto., California minimum wage. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger., Anne M. Skidmore. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Ethel M. Smith., Minimum wage in Washington, D.C. and Oregon, manufacturers' arguments and problems. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Chester Rowell., Rowell's introduction of President Wilson in San Francisco Civic Auditorium, September 17, 1919; League of Nations. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - William Gardiner., Statistical data. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Chester Rowell--Joseph C. Rowell., Hiram Johnson's arguments in opposition to League of Nations. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Chester Rowell., Hiram Johnson and League of Nations, Johnson's temperament, Edward A. Dickson, Meyer Lissner. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Mary anderson., Need for statistics on women wage-earners supporting dependents. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Harold L. Ickes--Meyer Lissner. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Harold Ickes--Will H. Hays., Objection to Hays' appointment of a Republican Party council dominated by conservatives, Howell, George W. Perkins, Walter Brown, Raymond Robins, White, Progressives in Republican Party, Charles Evans Hughes. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Chester Rowell., Rowell's editorial on Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - (January-June 1920), 64 pieces
    - Chester Rowell., Hiram Johnson's platform, Meyer Lissner, Herschel L. Carnahan. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Meyer Lissner., Herbert Hoover and the nomination, Will H. Hays, Democratic and Republican Parties, Hiram Johnson's platform, Eustace Cullinan. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Meyer Lissner., Will H. Hays, Mary S. Gibson, Katherine Philips Edson's newspaper interview, Hiram Johnson, Herschel L. Carnahan. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Harriet E. Vittum., Campaign for Leonard Wood. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Meyer Lissner., Hiram Johnson's candidacy for presidential nomination, Herbert Hoover's strategy. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Chester Rowell., Book on mental science, attitude toward philosophy. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - (telegram) Mrs. W.A. Fitzgerald., Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Chester Rowell., Mrs. Rowell and politics. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Meyer Lissner. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Chester Rowell., Introductions for Katherine Philips Edson to Harold Ickes and Medill McCormick. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Chester Rowell--Harold Ickes., Introduction for Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Chester Rowell., Mrs. Rowell's support for Herbert Hoover, John M. Keynes' The Economic Consequences of the Peace, questions of injustice in treaty ending World War I, judgments on the personalities of the Big Four, Elihu Root, League of Nations, Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - (telegram) Hiram Johnson., Thanks for loyalty. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Will H. Hays., Thanks for hospitality and good work. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Mayme Ober Peak., Article about possible First Ladies including Mrs. Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Harry A. Encell., Hiram Johnson and Herbert Hoover, J.R. Millar. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - J.R. Millar--Harry A. Encell., Minimum wage raise, Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Hiram Johnson, Jr., Mrs. Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - W.B. Mathews., Appointment of Katherine Philips Edson to Los Angeles County Johnson for President Campaign Committee. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Cornelia B. Pinchot--Meyer Lissner., Herbert Hoover, Hiram Johnson, Theodore Roosevelt. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - A. DeNyse., Work for Johnson campaign. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - (telegram) Clarence Darrow., Pledge for Hiram Johnson; Scripps, Herbert Hoover. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - (telegram) Carrie C. Catt., Asking Katherine Philips Edson's help in Connecticut campaign. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Meyer Lissner., Election campaign. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - (telegram) Meyer Lissner., Campaign speeches and luncheon. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - (telegram) Meyer Lissner., Margaret Dreier Robins and Raymond Robins speaking engagements. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Meyer Lissner., Luncheon. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Jessica B. Peixotto., Industrial Welfare Commission and Jessica Peixotto speech. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins., Regretting inability to work for Hiram Johnson in California. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins--Meyer Lissner., Hiram Johnson and issues: civil liberties, intervention in Russia, League of Nations, woman suffrage, 8-hour law, labor. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Jessica B. Peixotto., Industrial Welfare Commission, misunderstanding. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Hiram Johnson., Thanks for helping in California victory. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Hiram Johnson., Thanks. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - V.S. McClatchy., Suggested planks for Republican National Convention, trans-Pacific news communication, immigration restrictions. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Gertrude E. Beebe., Better America Federation and Commercial Federation attack on minimum wage and 8-hour laws. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - L.F. Parton., William Kent's senatorial candidacy and Progressive record, Samuel Shortridge's earlier attacks on Hiram Johnson, Pop Hamilton. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Meyer Lissner., William H. Crocker, Mary S. Gibson, Katherine Philips Edson's appointment to Republican Executive Committee. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Will H. Hays., Organizing 20 million new women voters, women on Republican Executive Committee. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - (July-December 1920), 116 pieces
    - Hiram Johnson., Appreciation for California support at Republican National Convention. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Harry M. Daugherty., Official notification of Warren G. Harding on his nomination, celebration dinner. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Will H. Hays., Meeting of Republican Executive Committee. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Conditions for serving on National Executive Committee, Warren G. Harding should get 36th state needed for ratification of suffrage amendment, Will H. Hays, Harding, Governor Clement of Vermont, members of Executive Committee. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Will H. Hays. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Warren Harding., Asking for interview with Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) George B. Christian, Jr. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Mary anderson., New raise in California minimum wage. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Meyer Lissner. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Meyer Lissner. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Helen Bary., Washington, Children's Bureau of Department of Labor, Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Elmer Dover., Oregon organization. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Elmer Dover., Oregon and Washington organization, speakers: Mrs. Douglas Robinson, Mrs. Medill McCormick, Miss Freeman, Mrs. Morrison. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Will D. Hays. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Cornelia Pinchot., Republican Executive Committee, Gifford Pinchot and Warren G. Harding, Hiram Johnson, Leonard Wood. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Elsa Lissner. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Belle., James Cox on League of Nations and Hiram Johnson, publicity for women's work in campaign. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Mary S. Gibson., Republican Party leaders attacking social legislation, Hoademan attacking Labor Commission and Dr. Simon Lubin, Better America Federation. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland., Katherine Philips Edson speaking engagements, Hiram Johnson or Calvin Coolidge should speak to offset effect of James Cox and F.D. Roosevelt, election campaign. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Adah E. Bush., Meeting of Margaret D. Robins, Mrs. Edwards, Warren G. Harding, Child on issues interesting women, Lou Henry Hoover, Social Justice Committee. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Raymond Benjamin., Campaign, Hiram Johnson's speaking tour. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland., Robert N. Stanfield's campaign. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Hiram Johnson., Itinerary undecided. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Adah E. Bush. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bertha S. Newland., Idaho outlook for Harding and for Senate race, Clara Burdette, comment on Katherine Philips Edson's stressing of Hiram Johnson in speeches. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Mrs. F.C. Northrup. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Adah E. Bush., Bertha S. Newland.; News clipping from Fresno Republican: Johnson influence on Harding and others regarding League of Nations issue. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bertha S. Newland., Personal problem with campaign work. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bertha S. Newland., Campaign in Oregon and Washington. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bertha S. Newland., Idaho politics, William E. Borah, Frank R. Gooding. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Simplicity Adjustable Collar Pin Company., Campaign buttons. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - ?., Election campaign, James M. Cox, Democratic slander of Warren G. Harding. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Chester Rowell., Hiram Johnson, Warren G. Harding. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Adah E. Bush., Bertha S. Newland, campaign. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Marie Stuart Edwards., Two Indiana counties need Hiram Johnson to speak for Warren G. Harding. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Marie Stuart Edwards., Marion meeting, Progressivism, Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Belle Cooley., Bertha Newland. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland., William E. Borah, Frank R. Gooding, problems. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Horace Kimball., Washington campaign asking for big speakers, Bertha Newland problem. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Charles Hebberd. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Mrs. Manley L. Fosseen. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) John L. Day., Asking Hiram Johnson's recommendation for Robert N. Stanfield. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bertha S. Newland., Miss Newland's rejection in Washington, Elizabeth Poindexter, Charles Hebberd, Clara Burdette, William E. Borah, Hart. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) John L. Day. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Will H. Hays., Herbert Hoover's (telegram)egram to Clara Burdette. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Charles Hebberd., Bertha S. Newland. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Belle Cooley., Bertha S. Newland. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Harriet Taylor Upton. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Rosa Lee., Bertha S. Newland. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Will H. Hays., Appreciation for cooperation, responsibility in politics for maladministration. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) T.B. Neuhausen., Bertha S. Newland, Hiram Johnson. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland., Plans. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Evelyn N. Louisson. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Thomas H. Tongue, Jr. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Mrs. F.O. Northrup. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Adah E. Bush., Bertha S. Newland. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Adah E. Bush. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Clarence R. Hotchkiss. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Mrs. W.W. Remmington. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Belle Cooley. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - G.H. Whipple., Election campaign. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Will H. Hays., Republican Executive Committee meeting. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Effie S. Lazard. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Elizabeth McDonald. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Bertha S. Newland. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Margaret Damrosch-- Harriet Taylor Upton., Rejecting anti-League of Nations stand of women Republicans' magazine. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Mrs. F.O. Northrup, Evelyn Louisson., Congratulations on victory; Robert N. Stanfield's winning. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Harriet Taylor Upton. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Post-election plans of Republican women, Ruth McCormick, League of Women Voters. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - (telegram) Florence Kling Harding., Thanks for congratulations and for campaign work. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Men and women in political organization, post-election plans, Will H. Hays. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Harriet T. Upton., Ruth McCormick, Will H. Hays, California in election. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Ruth McCormick., Republican women's plans, League of Women Voters. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Women in government. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Felix Frankfurter., Equalizing industrial conditions among different states, constitutional question on legislation such as Child Labor Law and minimum wage, Supreme Court. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence (1921-1933)
  - (January-October 1921), 37 pieces
    - (telegram) Dr. George Whipple., Medical students' class schedules. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Republican Federation of Women--discussion of name of Republican women's organization. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Harriet Taylor Upton., Republican women's organization, Mrs. Liver-more, women's spirit. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Hiram Johnson. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins., International Congress of Working Women, U.S. agriculture. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Fred Boegle, Jr.--Ben F. Schlesinger., Requesting endorsement of minimum wage law. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Ben F. Schlesinger--Fred Boegle, Jr., Endorsing minimum wage. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Hiram Johnson., Relations between Mrs. Warren Harding and Mrs. Hiram Johnson, Mrs. anderson. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Meyer Lissner., Relations between Mrs. Harding and Mrs. Johnson, asking for information on Mabel Willebrandt, Mrs. anderson. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - (telegram) Hiram Johnson., Asking for endorsements from California Republican Women for Mabel Willebrandt. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Margaret Dreier Robins., Mary Macarthur memorial, exchange of young labor leaders between Britain and America. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bill F. Dunning(?)--Meyer Lissner. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Meyer Lissner. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Meyer Lissner., Maternity bill. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Hiram Johnson., Possibility of Chester Rowell taking over Los Angeles Examiner, land office position. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Marie L. Obenauer., Applicants for an office, Senator Boies Penrose and Senator Philander C. Knox. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Meyer Lissner., Hiram Johnson, John P. McLaughlin, successor to Annette Adams, Alexander McCabe, Teague and Powell (big citrus men), William D. Stephens. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Harry M. Daugherty., Assistant Attorney General appointment. (Box 3, Folder 1)